Pitt Jazz Collection, 1971-2011 UA.90.8.26.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Audio/Video Material, 1973-1999; VII.
  - Video Recordings, Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert, 1974-1999; 2.
    - 16th Annual Seminar, 1986
      - Trumpet Workshop with Jon Faddis, 1986 (Box 14, Video 4)
      - Drums Workshop with Akira Tana, 1986 (Box 14, Video 5)
    - 17th Annual Seminar, 1987
      - Market Your Talent with George Butler and Guest Artist Harry Conic, 1987 (Box 14, Video 6)
      - Bass Workshop with Ray Drummond, 1987 (Box 14, Video 7)
      - Drums Workshop with Idris Muhammad | Saxophone Workshop with Grover Washington, Jr., 1987 (Box 14, Video 8)
      - Keyboards Workshop with Patrice Rushen, 1987 (Box 14, Video 9)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Mike Mossman, 1987 (Box 14, Video 10)
      - Synthesizers Workshop with Phillip Woo, 1987 (Box 14, Video 11)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Marvin "Smitty" Smith, 1987 (Box 14, Video 12)
      - Rehearsal and Performance Techniques with Jimmy Owens and Stage Band, 1987 (Box 14, Video 13)
    - 18th Annual Seminar, 1988
      - Saxophone Workshop with Grover Washington, Jr., 1988 (Box 14, Video 14)
      - Drums Workshop with Billy Cobham, 1988 (Box 14, Video 15)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Freddie Hubbard, 1988 (Box 14, Video 16)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Terence Blanchard, 1988 (Box 14, Video 17)
    - 19th Annual Seminar, 1989
      - The State of Soviet Jazz, 1989 (Box 14, Video 18)
      - The Business of Jazz with Donald Byrd and Charles Fishman, 1989 (Box 14, Video 19)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Arturo Sandoval, 1989 (Box 14, Video 20)
      - Saxophone Workshop with Johnny Griffin, 1989 (Box 14, Video 21)
      - Piano Workshop with Patrice Rushen, 1989 (Box 14, Video 22)
      - Jazz Seminar Workshop with Mikhail Alperin, 1989 (Box 14, Video 23)
      - Bass Workshop with Abraham Laboriel, 1989 (Box 14, Video 24)
      - Drums Workshop with Idris Muhammad, 1989 (Box 14, Video 25)
    - 20th Annual Seminar
      - Promotional Video Featuring Dr. Nathan Davis, 1990 (Box 16, Video 28)
      - Direct From Bombay: Jazz Critic Niranjan Jhaveri featuring Soloist D. Pandit, 1990 (Box 14, Video 26)
      - The Business of Music with Paul Silverthorn: Attorney and Personal Manager for Grover Washington, Jr., 1990 (Box 14, Video 27)
      - Pittsburgh Jazz Orchestra with Special Guest Soloist Marcio Montarroyos, Direct from Rio de Janeiro, 1990 (Box 14, Video 28)
      - Bass Workshop with Ray Drummond, 1990 (Box 14, Video 29)
      - Piano Workshop with Ellis Marsalis, 1990 (Box 14, Video 30)
      - Saxophone Workshop with Grover Washington, Jr., 1990 (Box 14, Video 31)
      - Guitar Workshop with Kevin Eubanks, 1990 (Box 16, Video 1)
      - Drums Workshop with Terri L. Carrington, 1990 (Box 16, Video 2)
      - Flute Workshop with Herbie Mann, 1990 (Box 16, Video 3)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Jon Faddis, 1990 (Box 16, Video 4)
    - 21st Annual Seminar, 1991
      - Inside the Music Business with Steve Backer and Ina Dittke, 1991 (Box 16, Video 5)
      - Piano Workshop with Kenny Barron, 1991 (Box 16, Video 6)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Mike Mossman, 1991 (Box 16, Video 7)
      - Saxophone Workshop with Ernie Watts, 1991 (Box 16, Video 8)
      - "The Expatriate Jazz Musician in Europe" with Ursula Davis, 1991 (Box 16, Video 9)
      - "Music Medicine: Insights into the Physiological and Psychological Aspects of Performance" with Peter Wehling, 1991 (Box 16, Video 10)
      - Drums Workshop with Alan Dawson, 1991 (Box 16, Video 11)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Arturo Sandoval, 1991 (Box 16, Video 12)
      - 21st Annual Concert, 1991 (Box 16, Video 13-14)
    - 22nd Annual Seminar, 1992
      - Trumpet Workshop with Art Farmer, 1992 (Box 16, Video 15)
      - Drums Workshop with Idris Muhammad, 1992 (Box 16, Video 16)
      - Bass Workshop with Miroslav Vitous, 1992 (Box 16, Video 17)
      - The History of Jazz: A Lecture with Leonard Feather, author of The Encyclopedia of Jazz, 1992 (Box 16, Video 18)
      - Guitar Workshop with Philip Catherine, 1992 (Box 16, Video 19)
      - Piano Workshop with Mulgrew Miller, 1992 (Box 16, Video 20)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Jimmy Owens, 1992 (Box 16, Video 21)
      - Saxophone Workshop with Grover Washington, Jr., 1992 (Box 16, Video 22)
      - 22nd Annual Concert, 1992; 10. (Box 16, Video 23)
    - 23rd Annual Seminar, 1993
      - Tenor Saxophone Workshop with Benny Golson, 1993 (Box 16, Video 24)
      - Drums with Terri Lyne Carrington, 1993 (Box 16, Video 25)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Randy Brecker, 1993 (Box 16, Video 26)
      - Trombone Workshop with Curtis Fuller, 1993 (Box 16, Video 27)
      - Guitar Workshop with Kevin Eubanks, 1993 (Box 17, Video 1)
      - Composing and Arranging Workshop with Clare Fisher, 1993 (Box 17, Video 2)
      - Inside the Music Business with Michele Adams and George Butler, 1993 (Box 17, Video 3)
      - Bass Workshop with Percy Heath, 1993 (Box 17, Video 4)
      - Promotional Video, 1993 (Box 17, Video 5)
    - 25th Annual Seminar, 1995
      - Music Production Workshop with Paul Silverthorn, 1995 (Box 17, Video 6)
      - Reeds Workshops With James Moody and Grover Washington, Jr., 1995 (Box 17, Video 7)
      - Drums Workshop with Idris Muhammad, 1995 (Box 17, Video 8)
      - Sound Engineering with Dae Bennett, 1995 (Box 17, Video 9)
      - Piano Workshop with Patrice Rushen, 1995 (Box 17, Video 10)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Jon Faddis, 1995 (Box 17, Video 11)
    - 26th Annual Seminar, 1996
      - Trumpet Workshop with Benny Bailey, 1996 (Box 17, Video 12)
      - Bass Workshop with Abraham Laboriel, 1996 (Box 17, Video 13)
      - Flute Workshop with Herbie Mann, 1996 (Box 17, Video 14)
      - The Music Industry with Marvin Witofsky, 1996 (Box 17, Video 15)
      - Piano Workshop with Mulgrew Miller, 1996 (Box 17, Video 16)
      - Drums Workshop with T.S. Monk, 1997 (Box 17, Video 17)
      - Saxophone Workshop with Johnny Griffin, 1996 (Box 17, Video 18)
    - 27th Annual Seminar, 1997
      - Tenor Saxophone Workshop with Ernie Watts, 1997 (Box 17, Video 19)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Jimmy Owens, 1997 (Box 17, Video 20)
      - Trumpet Workshop with Terumasa Hino, 1997 (Box 17, Video 21)
      - Trombone Workshop with Curtis Fuller, 1997 (Box 17, Video 22)
      - Alto Saxophone Workshop with Jackie McLean, 1997 (Box 17, Video 23)
      - Bass Workshop with John Patitucci, 1997 (Box 17, Video 24)
    - 28th Annual Concert, 1998
      - World Beat: The Influences of Latin Rhythms in Jazz with Abraham Laboriel, 1998 (Box 17, Video 25)
      - The Magic of Jazz: The Flute as a Solo Jazz Instrument with Herbie Mann, 1998 (Box 17, Video 26)
      - Artistry and Rhythm: A History of Drums in Jazz with Idris Muhamad, 1998 (Box 17, Video 27)
      - Bridging the Gap: From Classical to Jazz with George Cables and Larry Coryell, 1998 (Box 17, Video 28)
      - 28th Annual Concert, 1998 (Box 29-30)
  - Jazz Studies at the University of Pittsburgh, 3.
    - University of Pittsburgh Jazz Ensemble LIVE! Montreux, Switzerland, 1983 (Box 21, Record 1)
    - Montreux Jazz Festival, 1973 (Box 18, Reel 1-2)
    - General Recording, 1974 (Box 18, Reel 3)
    - Western Penitentiary Concert, 1977 (Box 18, Reel 4-6)
    - General Recording, 1977 (Box 18, Reel 7)
    - "Black America- Martin Luther King in Memoriam", ca. 1971-2001 (Box 18, Reel 8)
    - General Recording, ca. 1971-2001 (Box 18, Reel 9)
    - April Concert, ca. 1971-2001 (Box 18, Reel 10)
    - Concert at St. Mary's Hall Port of Spain, Trinidad & Tobago, 1980 (Box 18, Reel 11-12)
    - General Recording, 1980 (Box 18, Reel 13)
    - University of Pittsburgh Jazz Ensemble Recording, 1981 (Box 18, Reel 14)
    - Jazz Concert, ca. 1971-2001 (Box 18, Reel 15-17)
    - Winter Concert, 1982 (Box 18, Video 1-2)
    - Rehearsal, 1983 (Box 19, Cassette 1)
    - General Recording, 1985 (Box 19, Cassette 2)
    - Spring Concert with Jon Faddis, 1985 (Box 19, Cassette 3-4)
    - Spring Concert, 1989 (Box 19, Cassette 5)
    - General Recording, 1991 (Box 19, Cassette 6)
    - "Mean What You Say", ca. 1983-1999 (Box 19, Cassette 7)
    - Concert Featuring Joe Williams, ca. 1983-1999 (Box 19, Cassette 8)
    - Spring Concert Featuring Monty Alexander, 1995 (Box 19, Cassette 9-10)
    - Spring Concert, 1997 (Box 19, Cassette 11-12)
  - Nathan Davis, 4.
    - Paris Reunion Band at Ronnie Scott's, London, UK, 1982 (Box 20, Cassette 1)
    - "Three Pieces" Solo for Violin by Nathan Davis, 1984 (Box 20, Cassette 2)
    - "Three Pieces" as performed by Jenny Spanoghe and J. Herbein, 1984 (Box 20, Cassette 3)
    - Master Copy: Just Above My Head by Nathan Davis, 1985 (Box 20, Cassette 4)
    - "Just Above My Head" overture through rehearsal "y" Jazz improvisation on demo tape by Vince Genova, ca. 1985 (Box 20, Cassette 5)
    - Bishop Granville's Church Barbados, 1986 (Box 20, Cassette 6)
    - January 10th Jazz Improv Session, ca. 1980-1989 (Box 20, Cassette 7)
    - Book Dictation, ca. 1980-1999 (Box 20, Cassette 8)
    - Office Notes: The Study of Ethnomusicology at the University of Pittsburgh, ca. 1980-1999 (Box 20, Cassette 9)
    - Unidentified Cassette: Books and Miscellaneous, ca. 1980-1989 (Box 20, Cassette 10)
    - Interview with Joe Sanford conducted by David S. Miller, 1994 (Box 20, Cassette 11)
    - Slippery Rock State College Workshop, 1973 (Box 20, Reel 1)
    - An Opinion on Jazz Trumpet, ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 2)
    - PSA Expressions of Excellence: A Festival of Hispanic, Native American and Black Arts, ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 3)
    - Interview: Yoruba Tribe of U.S., ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 4)
    - Doc Holiday, ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 5)
    - Rehearsal with Nathan Davis, 1978 (Box 20, Reel 6)
    - Afro Structural Conceptions Composed by Nathan Davis, ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 7)
    - Unidentified Interview, ca. 1971-1989 (Box 20, Reel 8)
    - London By Night, 1987 (Box 21, Record 2)
  - Pittsburgh Jazz Artists, 1955-1985; 5.
    This series contains albums and documentary footage of legendary Jazz artists from the Pittsburgh area, including Erroll Garner, Earl 'Fatha' Hines, Maxine Sullivan, George Benson and others.
    - George Benson, Give me the Night, 1980 (Box 21, Record 3)
    - Herold Betters, Do Anything you Wanna, 1966 (Box 21, Record 4)
    - Earl Hines, The Art of Jazz Piano, 1956 (Box 21, Record 5)
    - Kenny Clarke, featured on Birth of the Cool by Miles Davis, 1957 (Box 21, Record 6)
    - Erroll Garner, Concert by the Sea, 1955 (Box 22, Record 1)
    - Erroll Garner, Master of the Keyboard, 1981 (Box 22, Record 2)
    - Erroll Garner, Starring the Magic Artistry of Erroll Garner, 1966 (Box 22, Record 3)
    - Sammy Nestico, Night Flight, 1985 (Box 22, Record 4)
    - Maxine Sullivan, Family Library of Music: Jazz Hall of Fame, 1963 (Box 22, Record 5)
    - Maxine Sullivan: Love to be in Love, B-roll footage, ca. 1991 (Box 23-28)